# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hi everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
Today I will share the recipe of a homestyle dish
# 冬瓜烧排骨
Braised Pork Ribs with White Gourd
# 首先我们准备精排骨500克
First, prepare 500 gram of lean pork ribs
# 将每一根分开之后剁成小块备用
Separate and chop into small pieces
# 同学们最好剁小块一些
You can chop it into smaller pieces …
# 这样更加容易炒熟
… which are easier to cook
# 下一步开始处理排骨
Next, prepare the ribs
# 盆中加入1小把食用盐（约10克）
In a pot, add 10 gram of salt
# 加入小苏打3克
Add 3 gram of baking soda
# 加小苏打的目的是破坏排骨中的肌纤维增加嫩度
Baking soda adds tenderness by breaking up muscle fibers
# 然后先加入少量的清水抓洗3分钟
Rinse with water for 3 minutes …
# 这样可以去除排骨中残留的血水
… to remove blood remaining in the ribs
# 3分钟之后加入清水清洗干净
3 minters later, add more water to rinse
# 然后再捞出挤干水份备用
Drain and squeeze to remove water
# 同学们这一步必须多清洗几遍
The cleaning step must be repeated for several times
# 下一步开始腌制排骨
Next is to marinate the ribs
# 盆中加入少许食用盐（约0.5克）
In a pot, add 0.5 gram of salt
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a few ground pepper
# 加入蚝油3克
Add 3 gram of oyster sauce
# 加入蛋黄1个之后搅拌均匀（鸡蛋黄）
Add 1 yolk and stir (chicken egg yolk)
# 再加入适量的干淀粉收紧水份（约4克）
And add a reasonable amount (about 4g) of dry starch to absorb water
# 最后加入少许的植物油拌匀
Finally add a little vegetable oil and stir well
# 加植物油可以防止排骨下锅粘连
Vegetable oil avoids the ribs from sticking to wok
# 下一步开始处理冬瓜
Next, we prepare white gourd
# 准备冬瓜500克去皮之后切成小块备用
Peel 500 gram of white gourd and cut into pieces
# 不喜欢冬瓜的同学可以用土豆或者芋头代替
If you do not like white gourd, you can replace it with potato or taro
# 下一步开始准备料头
Next, prepare aromatics
# 准备大蒜几颗切成小粒备用（约20克）
Cut 20 gram of garlic into pieces
# 准备生姜1小块切成姜粒备用
Cut up one piece of ginger
# 最后准备适量的小米辣切碎备用
Finally, cut up some "Xiaomila" chili pepper
# 不能吃辣的同学可以不加
Skip the pepper if you do not like
# 下一步开始制作
Next start cooking
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First, we add a reasonable amount of water into the wok
# 加入1小勺食用盐
Add 1 tbsp of salt
# 然后将切好的冬瓜下锅焯水1分钟
Add the white gourd and blanch for 1 minute
# 这一步的目的是去除冬瓜的生味
This helps remove raw odor from the white gourd
# 中途再加入少许的植物油保色
Add a little vegetable oil midway to preserve color
# 焯水1分钟之后倒出备用
Blanch for 1 minute
# 下一步开始爆排骨
Next, we fry the ribs
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Heat up the wok then add some oil to grease the wok
# 然后将热油倒出再加入适量的底油
After pouring out the heated oil, we add some base oil
# 油温5成热之后将腌制好的排骨下锅
Add the marinated ribs as oil temperature reach 150°C/302°F
# 排骨下锅之后先不翻动煎30秒
After adding the ribs, fry for 30 seconds without stirring …
# 这一步的目的是防止脱浆
… to avoid losing slurry on the ribs
# 煎30秒钟之后再翻动均匀
After frying 30 seconds, stir well
# 煎至排骨略微金黄之后倒出多余的植物油
Stir till ribs are slightly golden brown, then drain excessive vegetable oil
# 油倒完之后再将排骨重新下锅
After draining the oil, replace the ribs into the wok
# 加入切好的姜蒜辣椒粒开中火爆香
Add aromatics (diced ginger, garlic, and pepper) and fry with medium heat
# 料头爆香之后加入适量的红油豆瓣酱（约10克）
After frying the aromatics, add 10 gram of chili oil doubanjiang
# 然后转小火将豆瓣酱炒香炒出红油
Switch to low heat and fry till you see red oil
# 再加入适量的料酒从锅边淋入
Add Chinese cooking wine from the side of the wok
# 翻炒几下之后将焯好水的冬瓜下锅
Stir-fry several times and add blanched white gourd
# 再加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Add some water and boil with high heat
# 大火烧开之后转小火烧25分钟
Upon boiling, switch to low heat for 25 minutes
# 排骨烧至20分钟之后开始调味
Begin seasoning 20 minutes into the low heat
# 锅中加入食用盐1克
In the wok, add 1 gram of salt
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add a little ground pepper
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
Add a little sugar to enhance umami
# 加入鸡精1克
Add 1 gram of chicken bouillon
# 调好味之后继续烧5分钟
Continue to cook for 5 minutes after seasoning
# 5分钟之后将锅离火加入适量的水淀粉勾芡
After 5 minutes, add some slurry
# 水淀粉下锅之后再开中火烧开
After adding slurry, cook with medium heat till boiling
# 最后再加入少许明油即可出锅装盘
Last, add a little Ming You (literally "oil for a shiny presence") and plate
# 一道口感软嫩入味的冬瓜烧排骨就制作完成
A dish of tender and flavorful Braised Pork Ribs with White Gourd is ready to serve
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, technical summary
第一，最好选择嫩排骨，否则老排骨需要增加烧制的时间
First, tender ribs are preferred over rigid ones. Rigid ribs demand longer cooking time
第二，冬瓜不能烧太久否则很容易化成水
Second, white gourd cannot be cooked for too long or it will turn into water
第三，不能吃辣的同学可以不加豆瓣酱和辣椒用蚝油香菇代替
Third, if you cannot eat spicy food, doubanjiang and pepper can be replaced with oyster sauce and shiitake mushroom
烧排骨的技术总结完毕
That is all for the technical summary